# Nicholas Ceccarelli

Software Engineer

I am a software engineer with experience in frontend, IoT edge, and backend development. I have developed .NET microservices orchestrated with Kubernetes, Azure IoT Edge modules in C# and Python housed in Docker containers, iOS apps with SwiftUI, and Azure Infrastructure using Terraform. I also have experience in systems programming in C and C++ and frontend web development in React and Razor Pages.

## WORK EXPERIENCE



## Full Stack Software Engineer, Moog Inc.

Aug. 2021 - Present

LinkedIn: nceccarelli

Email: njceccarelli@gmail.com

- Contributed to PI and sprint planning for the department
- Discussed requirements with users, ran A/B tests, and made improvements from feedback
- Owned features from ideation and diagraming to development, testing, and deployment

## Platform/Backend Experience

- Created a platform of microservices to manage and display hierarchy, messaging, telemetry, state, & errors from edge devices, which can be applied to any IoT project, and is exposed via an API
- Taken ownership of Microsoft Azure infrastructure deployments via Terraform. This solution emphasizes code reusability by treating Azure resources as objects
- Taken ownership of CI/CD process for infrastructure and code deployments using Azure DevOps build and release pipelines, Docker containerization, and Kubernetes orchestration

## IoT Edge Experience

Developed an extensive framework of telemetry-collecting edge modules for a wide variety of edge devices including vehicles and factory equipment that can be customized for clients

## **Frontend Experience**

- Taken ownership of an SwiftUI-based iOS app to display entities and telemetry data using tables and charts. The app also allows users to report information about edge devices.
- Contributed to a Razor Pages website with the same objectives as the iOS application

## **Software Engineering Intern**, *Moog Inc.*

July 2020 - May 2021

#### **Software Engineering Consultant**, Ox Intel

May 2020 – Aug. 2020

- Developed a minimum viable product GUI & data storage system for a data-intensive application, which resulted in obtaining a \$50,000 Department of Defense grant
- Assisted the Ox team by teaching the basics of software development & cloud computing

# **EDUCATION**



**Boston University** 

Master of Science, Software Development

Expected May 2024

University at Buffalo, The State University of New York

Graduated May 2021

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Software Systems Focus Bachelor of Arts. Mathematics

GPA: 3.96/4.00

PROGRAMMING PROJECTS



Social Media React Website

Jan. 2021 - May 2021

- Developed a React-based social media platform centered around images
- Worked on a team of five for a Human-Computer Interaction class

## C-Standard Compliant Memory Allocator

Apr. 2019

- Implemented malloc(), calloc(), realloc(), & free() memory allocation functions for the C language
- Utilized a multi-pool approach for small allocations & a bulk approach for large allocations

## SKILLS



Languages (in order of proficiency): C#, Python, Swift, C++, C, Java, JavaScript

Enterprise skills: Agile & SAFe Development, Unit & Integration Testing, Azure DevOps (incl. CI/CD pipelines) Frameworks & Environments: .NET 6.0, ASP.NET Razor Pages, SwiftUI (iOS), Android Development, React Azure technologies: IoT Hub, CosmosDB, Storage Account, Key Vault, VM, AAD, Logic Apps, Function Apps Other technologies: Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, Terragrunt, Dapr, Helm, Git Version Control, Bash Scripts Also proficient in: System Design, Team Management, Collaboration, Communication